{
    "id": "8ec99e7e9b2d4c549de338e4bac08b70",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Help me with this, ………………….?",
            "description": "After imperatives, will you is used to ask people to do things.",
            "answers": [
                "will you",
                "can't you",
                "won't you"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Politics ……………………… a dirty game.",
            "description": "Words like politics, science and mathematics are singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The girls in this photo ………………………….. my cousins.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the plural noun girls. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. my grandparents yesterday.",
            "description": "To call on is to visit.",
            "answers": [
                "called up",
                "called on",
                "called out"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither of these answers ………………………….. correct.",
            "description": "Use a singular verb after either and neither. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. in Mumbai at that time.",
            "description": "Use the simple past to talk about a completely finished event or situation. ",
            "answers": [
                "live",
                "lived",
                "have lived"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My application …………………………… by the company.",
            "description": "In the simple past, the passive form is made with was/were + past participle form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "has rejected",
                "was rejected",
                "had been rejected"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I am writing a novel. A novel …………………………….. by me.",
            "description": "The passive form of the present continuous is made with is/am/are + being + past participle.",
            "answers": [
                "is written",
                "was written",
                "is being written"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Let’s …………………………….. your plans.",
            "description": "Discuss is one of those verbs that cannot be followed by a preposition. ",
            "answers": [
                "discuss about",
                "discuss",
                "discuss on"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "That child …………………………….. neither of his parents.",
            "description": "Resemble does not take a preposition. ",
            "answers": [
                "resembles to",
                "resembles",
                "resembles with"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………………. to hear from them for a long time.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "are waiting",
                "have been waiting",
                "were waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. all my life in India.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more appropriate here. ",
            "answers": [
                "lived",
                "have lived",
                "am living"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}